

■ trailynne@gmail.com www.TraiLynne.org **424) 227-2059** Aurora, Colorado

in trai-lynne-compton/ TraiLynne

# **SUMMARY**

Technology is my passion and I pride myself on being able to build a website from thought to launch. My mission is to continuously produce the best of my capacity by pushing past my comfort zone & challenging myself as I contribute my knowledge, creativity, and expertise as a Web Developer.

# **SKILLS**

FRONTEND: React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, UI/UX, Responsive Development, Bootstrap, SASS, Bootstrap, Flexbox

BACKEND: Express.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, Ruby, MySQL, RDBMS

ADDITIONAL TECH SKILLS: Git, Testing, Python, C SOFT SKILLS: Strong Work Ethic,

Verbal & Non-Verbal Communication, Loyalty, Integrity, Problem-Solving, Adaptability, Tenacity, Resillience, Observation, Detail-Oriented, Punctuality, Reliability, Empathy, Organization

# **PROJECTS**

SYMPOSIUM Apr. 2019 to May 2019 - Was a key player in the creation of the admin page on an Open Source chat forum project soon to replace the schools existing

- chat medium
- Took on the challenge of redesigning the entire website for easier user navigation and better user experience according to specifications provided with InVision Prototype
- Assembled the User Management frontend using React and Redux
- Upgraded existing Express.js & Postgres backend with an additional database table and API endpoints for approving and denvina emails
- Collaborated daily with 2 remote Team members and our Team Lead

#### PROJECT COURSE CORRECT

Mar. 2019

- Performed as sole Backend Developer in the development of a job site for soon to be and recently released convicts entering the workforce
- Utilized an Express.js and SQLite3 to structure the backend API endpoints and database that are accessed by the frontend to display and update information
- Collaborated with 4 remote team members daily to ensure successful project execution in 1 week
- Assembled Application testing using Jest

# **EDUCATION**

#### LAMBDA SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Development 2019

An immersive hands-on Software Engineering and Computer Science Academy, with a curriculum that includes a project based curriculum. [Curriculum] UI & Responsive Design - JavaScript - Node.is - React - React Native - Redux - MySQL - RDBMS - Python - C - Data Structures - Algorithms - Computer Architecture - Computer Security

#### FLATIRON SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Development 2017

A rigorous self-paced course of study that prepares one for a career in web development by providing skills and experience necessary to obtain and excel in a software development job [Curriculum] Ruby - HTML & CSS - Object Orientation Object Relational Mapping & SQL - Rack - Sinatra - Rails - JavaScript - React - Node and Express

### **INSIGHT SCHOOL OF COLORADO**

High School Diploma General 2012

# **EMPLOYMENT**

## TRILOGY EDUCATION SERVICES

Teaching Assistant

Remote Nov. 2018 to Current

- Instruct as a remote member of the Denver University Live Online Coding Bootcamp team
- Guide students in the process of building web pages and applications including debugging and researching
- Demo code solutions and homework examples providing a high-level explanation via Zoom
- Develop students coding and interview skills by regularly reviewing their projects, git commits, and presentation skills providing constructive criticism and 1:1 tutoring
- Coordinated class content and agenda with remote instructional team to ensure objectives are fully understood

## CONDUENT

iOS Technical Support

Nov. 2017 to June 2018

- Provided exceptional customer service and technical support to iOS users

## Sr. Customer Service Representative

- Handpicked to launch a new campaign
- Trained new and existing agents on 2 sites - Chosen to train and lead Tier 2 team
- Promoted a positive work environment by coming up with competitions and events
- Increased productivity of US Bank campaign by introducing a new break tracking system
- Popularized a new question and escalation handling system adopted sitewide

#### **Customer Service Representative**

- Promoted in less than 3 months for exceptional customer service and proactively going above and beyond job duties

#### **Technical Support Representative**

- Regularly recognized for diligence and punctuality during team meetings

- Invited regularly to give pep talk and job tips to new training classes

## 24/7 INTOUCH

## **Customer Service Representative**

- Awarded Employee of the Month 3 times
- Created Work Order Template approved for use sitewide

Remote

San Antonio, TX Aug. 2015 to Nov. 2017

May 2015 to Aug. 2015

Englewood, CO

June 2013 to Jan. 2014

Aurora, CO June 2012 to May 2013